# SUMARY

I am an Odessa National University graduate with a bachelor's in Information. My passion for AI & Web3 extends to deep learning and computer vision. I am experienced in the whole production process, from prototyping through development to deployment and optimization. I am comfortable working in diverse teams, keeping up with field advancements, and discussing them with colleagues. I am creative and a problem solver who adapts quickly and efficiently, even under pressure.

#### **CONTACT**

EMAIL: tomindev520@gmail.com

#### **SKILLS**

- · Golang, Nodejs
- Web3
- Next, React Native, React,
- TensorFlow,
- PyTorch,
- Pandas,
- NumPy,
- GPT4,
- OpenCV,
- FastAPI,
- Python,
- Scikit-learn,
- Pandas,
- OpenAl LLM,
- AWS,
- Flask

## **ILLIA MELNYCHENKO**

### **Machine Learning Engineer**

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

Machine Learning, Data Analytics, Statistical Data Analysis, SAP, Analytics, Data Scientist, Predictive Analytics, Data Modeling, Artificial Intelligence (AI), Natural Language Processing (NLP), Chatbots, FastAPI, Python, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG), FNN, CNN, RNN, LSTM, GANs, GNN, RLN, Golang, Nodejs, Web3

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Machine Learning & Web3 Engineer | Capex

Oct 2022 - Jun 2024

- Developed Decentralized apps (DApps) using Web3.js and Solidity.
- Researched and implemented methods for training computer vision models to be robust in special weather conditions.
- Examined and executed several explainable AI (XAI) methods for image classification models.
- Developed a novel explanation method for semantic segmentation models that outperformed cutting-edge explanations.
- Built 3+ NFT contracts and Supported NFT marketplace using web3 integration and Solidity.
- Designed and managed 5+ large databases using node.js, ORM and SQL/No-SOL.

#### Backend Engineer | Deus Robots

Jan 2020 - Sep 2022

- Developed the backend of a restaurant curation mobile app using Golang, AWS lambda, PostgreSQL, and Elasticsearch.
- Defined the process for software development within the company.
- Grew the team to five engineers working on Golang, React Native, React and the like.
- Hired and managed a team of eight engineers for the development of the web app and mobile app.

#### Machine Learning Researcher | Datuum

Apr 2017 - Jan 2020

- Increased awareness of the company by creating tutorial and demos with TensorFlow that ran in the platform.
- Composed blog posts that were featured on several publications in Medium with thousands of views.
- Increased the competitive advantage of our product with an aesthetic model that was able to score the beauty of the images with a state of the art CNN model.
- Created a NLP model able to classify scientific papers in biotechnology.
- Organized production code related to XAI methods to simplify the process of contributing to other team members.

#### **EDUCATION**

Odessa National University, Ukuranie - 2015 - 2019

- Bachelor of Computer Science (BCompSc), Mathematics
- GPA 3.8